Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office audiovisual materials, 1967-2003 and undated RL.11360
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office audiovisual materials
1967-2003 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11360
24.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. JWT maintained an office in Detroit from 1909-1920 and reopened it in 1944. Collection includes videocassettes, CDs and DVDs of advertisements, speeches, presentations, historical campaign compilations; awards submissions, training materials and other materials. Companies represented include American Red Cross, Burger King, Delta Sigma Phi, Ford, Goodyear, Ogilvy & Mather, United Way, White Castle, and Young & Rubicam. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Arranged by format and resource item number.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Detroit Office audiovisual materials were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1993-2004.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following JWT collections held by the Hartman Center:
Account Files; Domestic Advertisements; Denis Lanigan papers; New York Media Center Audiovisual Materials.
Collection Overview
Includes videocassettes, CDs and DVDs of advertisements, speeches, presentations, historical campaign compilations; awards submissions, training materials and other materials. Companies represented include American Red Cross, Burger King, Delta Sigma Phi, Ford, Goodyear, Ogilvy & Mather, United Way, White Castle, and Young & Rubicam. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Michigan -- Detroit; Detroit (Mich.); John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; American Red Cross; Burger King Corporation; Delta Sigma Phi Fraternity; Ford Motor Company; Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company; Ogilvy & Mather; White Castle (Restaurant); Young & Rubicam
- Video Materials, 1967-2003 and undated; 1
  - 1984 Car Historical Reel; 46 spots (Box 1, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-001)
  - 1988 Advertising (Box 1, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-002)
  - 1998 Compilation Reel #1a (Box 1, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-003)
  - Action Sports Adventure Demo Reel, Undated (Box 1, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-004)
  - Adcrafter JWT Day Reel, 1992 (Box 1, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-005)
  - Advertising Age Best TV Commercials of 1990, 1991 (Box 1, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-006)
  - Advideo Journal Issue 1, Undated (Box 1, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-007)
    Scope and Contents
    Contents: Introducing Diet Coke; Animation the State of the Art; Kronenbourg (beer) Launch; Commercial Resource New Visual Techniques
  - Advideo Journal Issue 1, Undated (Box 1, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-008)
  - Advideo Journal Issue 2, Undated (Box 2, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-009)
    Contents: AIS/American Bell, O&M's Winning Presentation; Special Events Sponsorship Extending Your Advertising Dollar
  - Adweek Reel, 12 spots, 1991 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-010)
    Includes Ford, Goodyear, Silk Green House, Monroe, TMI, Akzo, Delta Dental
  - Adweek Reel, 12 spots, 1991 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-011)
  - Adweek Report Card, 1992 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-012)
    Includes Ford, Akzo Salt, Ford Dealer Association, Goodyear, Payless
  - All Staff Meeting Creative Spots, 1992 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-013)
  - All Staff Meeting Diversified Accounts (Bosch, Delta, Speedy, Monroe), 1990 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-014)
  - Allen Thomas Adcrafter Presentation, 1992 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-015)
  - Allen Thomas Adcrafter Presentation, 1992 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-016)
  - Allen Thomas Adcrafter Presentation, 1992 (Box 2, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-017)
  - American Management Association, The Thompson Way, 1991 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-018)
  - American Red Cross: Buddies for Life, 1988 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-019)
  - American Red Cross: Corporate Campaign, 1990 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-020)
  - American Red Cross: Presentation to Southeastern Michigan Region Buddies for Life Campaign, 1988 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-021)
  - An Inside Look at Outdoor Advertising parts 1-4, Undated (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-022)
  - Automotive Aftermarket Council; excerpts from jobber sessions, 1984 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-023)
    Topics: Clinics, counterfeit parts, discount stores, brand names, carb kits, co-op, factory reps
  - Beard Elementary School; Regional Advertising Group volunteer project, 1992 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-024)
  - BHTC spots, 1990 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-025)
  - The Big Picture #2, 1995 (Box 3, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-026)
  - Bill Thompson presentation to Board of Directors, 1992 (Box 4, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-027)
  - Blaise Newman reel for anniversary recognition dinner (spots from 1958-1983), 1989 (Box 4, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-028)
  - Blaise Newman reel (old spots), Undated (Box 4, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-029)
  - Board Meeting--Kellogg's, Warner-:Lambert and Kodak, 1988 (Box 4, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-030)
  - Boston Pulse Focus Groups Reaction to Chevy S-10 4WD Commercial, 1989 (Box 4, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-031)
  - Brad Lachman Productions: A Word from Our Sponsors, Undated (Box 4, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-032)
  - Brand Image presentation (11 spots), Undated (Box 4, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-033)
  - BTAA Winners, 1989 (Box 4, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-034)
  - Burger King: Simulation Spot-Buy Negotiation, Undated (Box 4, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-035)
  - Burt Manning: Full Line Car Winning, 1990 (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-036)
  - Can't Touch That: Tom Robertson on JWT Detroit, 1990 (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-037)
  - Case History Reel, Undated (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-038)
  - CBS This Morning: Bill Thompson on European Advertising, 1990 (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-039)
  - Champion Promotion, Undated (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-040)
  - Champion Spark Plugs co-op program 19:25, 1984 (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-041)
  - Channel 7 News with Bill Bonds and Robbie Timmons on Neon Art, 1990 (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-042)
  - Chuck Balestrino Eyes on Thompson tape, Undated (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-043)
  - Chuck Balestrino Eyes on Thompson tape, Undated (Box 5, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-044)
  - Coca-Cola Mean Joe Green, Undated (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-045)
  - Compilation reel, 1989 (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-046)
  - Commercials 1947-1982, Undated (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-047)
  - Commercials Compilation Reel 1, 1998 (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-048)
  - Commercials Compilation Reel 2, 1998 (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-049)
  - Commercials 1948-1982, Undated (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-050)
  - Consumer Behavior--All in the Family Funeral 20:00, Undated (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-051)
  - DeBeers "Infatuation", Undated (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-052)
  - Delta/HAP spots, Undated (Box 6, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-053)
  - Delta Sigma Pi--Career Planning for the 90s, 1991 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-054)
  - Desensitization of America (Arnold Grisman), 1976 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-055)
  - Detroit Center For All Staff Meeting, 1992 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-056)
  - Detroit Center Video for All Staff Meeting, 1992 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-057)
  - Detroit Employee Anniversary Recognition Awards, 1989 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-058)
  - Detroit Employee Anniversary Recognition Awards, 1990 (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-059)
  - Detroit Institute of the Arts history reel, Undated (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-060)
  - Dick Howting Presentation (Ford), Undated (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-061)
  - Dick Van Dyke Show, Undated (Box 7, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-062)
  - Don't Quit Your Day Job Talent Show, 1992 (Box 8, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-063)
  - Doug and the Slugs, Undated (Box 8, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-064)
  - Effective Advertising presentation by McCollum Spielman Research, 1989 (Box 8, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-065)
  - First Moments, Undated (Box 8, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-066)
  - Flippers: Changes in the Way Americans Watch TV, Undated (Box 8, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-067)
  - Ford Motor Company 1970 Historical "Nitro", 1991 (Box 8, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-068)
  - Ford 2000 MY Explorer Sport Trac: Sport Trac Challenge Video, 1999 (Box 8, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-069)
  - Ford, American Lung Association, Akzo spots, Undated (Box 8, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-070)
  - Ford Automotive Creative (6 spots), Undated (Box 8, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-071)
  - Ford 1991 Crown Victoria Animatics "Last Laugh", 1990 (Box 9, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-072)
  - Ford Crown Victoria Spot "Last Laugh", Undated (Box 9, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-073)
  - Ford Escort, Ranger spots, 1989 (Box 9, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-074)
  - Ford Explorer spots, 1990 (Box 9, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-075)
  - Ford Explorer "Valley" spot, 1991 (Box 9, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-076)
  - Ford Dealer Association weekly reels 5/12-7/21, 2003 (Box 9, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-077)
  - Ford Fiesta, 1999 (Box 9, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-078)
  - Ford Historical Spots, 1995 (Box 9, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-079)
  - Ford/JWT 50th Anniversary Observance (Peter Schweitzer, Burt Manning, Alex Trotman, Red Poling), 1993 (Box 9, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-080)
  - Ford/JWT 50th Anniversary Observance (Peter Schweitzer, Burt Manning, Alex Trotman, Red Poling), 1993 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-081)
  - Ford/JWT 50th Anniversary Observance (Peter Schweitzer, Burt Manning, Alex Trotman, Red Poling), 1993 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-082)
  - Ford Media Presentation Part 1, 1998 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-083)
  - Ford Media Presentation Part 2, 1998 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-084)
  - Ford Motorsports and other clients compilation, 1991 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-085)
    Includes: Ford Motorsports, Goodyear, Monroe, Delta Dental, Akza Salt, Bosch, Silk Green House, international commercials
  - Ford Mustang 35th anniversary montage, 1989 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-086)
  - Ford Mustang Historical Part 1, 1993 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-087)
  - Ford Mustang Historical Part 1, 1993 (Box 10, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-088)
  - Ford Mustang Loop, Undated (Box 10, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-089)
  - Ford Ranger video, Undated (Box 11, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-090)
  - Ford Star Response Comedy Central, Undated (Box 11, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-091)
  - Ford 1956 Thunderbird Announce (also 1964 Falcon, Mustang), Undated (Box 11, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-092)
  - Ford Thunderbird, Escort, 1990 (Box 11, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-093)
  - Ford Thunderbird "Words" Campaign 1983-1986, Undated (Box 11, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-094)
  - Ford Truck, Explorer spots, Undated (Box 11, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-095)
  - Ford Truck Man F-150, Undated (Box 11, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-096)
  - Ford Truck WCF, Focus, Thunderbird, Explorer, Undated (Box 11, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-097)
  - Ford Worldwide Direct Market Operations, Dubai International Auto Show Media Ride and Drive, 2001 (Box 12, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-098)
  - Ford "Under Here" Aerostar, 1990 (Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-099)
  - Gannet Outdoor Best National and International Spots, 1987 (Box 12, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-100)
  - George Black Review of European Advertising, 1986 (Box 12, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-101)
  - Good Old Days of Dealer TV, 1967 (Box 12, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-102)
  - Goodyear spots, Undated (Box 12, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-103)
  - Grace and Wild Studios Graphics and Paint Reel, 1990 (Box 12, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-104)
  - Grand Prix Promotion; Champion Spark Plug Trade Video, Undated (Box 12, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-105)
  - Highlights Review "Expectations of Our People" EPCOT Address by Joe O'Donnell, Undated (Box 13, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-106)
  - Holiday Health Spa Spots, 1990 (Box 13, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-107)
  - International Commercials Compilation, 1988 (Box 13, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-108)
  - JWT Can't Touch That and Other Spots, Undated (Box 13, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-109)
    Includes: Ford, Bosch, Detroit Police; Monroe, Delta Dental, Speedy
  - JWT Peter Schweitzer Speech, Advertising Research Foundation, 1990 (Box 13, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-110)
  - J. Walter Does That!, Undated (Box 13, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-111)
    Includes: Flippers, DeBeers, Kodak, Reebok, Teledyne, Vic Tanny international commercials
  - J. Walter Did That? Peter Schweitzer ARF Speech, 1990 (Box 13, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-112)
  - J. Walter Did That? and other spots, 1990 (Box 13, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-113)
    Includes: Mueslix, Kodak, Sheena Easton international commercials
  - J. Walter Does That!, 1990 (Box 14, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-114)
  - J. Walter Does That!, 1988 (Box 14, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-115)
    Includes: Chicago Health Clubs, Mueslix, Trident, Kodak, Matilda Bay, King Tuts
  - JWT 125th Anniversary Reel, 1989 (Box 14, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-116)
  - JWT 1985-1955, 1991 (Box 14, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-117)
  - JWT Archive Video "NYO", Undated (Box 14, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-118)
  - JWT Board Meeting: Ford A Brief History 11:47, Undated (Box 14, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-119)
  - JWT Ideas and Information: Managing Change The Role of Communications (Bill Ross, 1977 (Box 14, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-120)
  - JWT Learning Series: The Moving Target (Rena Bartos), 1977 (Box 14, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-121)
  - JWT Learning Series: Sales Promotion Trends in the United States (Jack Scollay), 1977 (Box 14, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-122)
  - JWT Learning Series: TV Violence in the Eyes of the Beholders (Joel Baumwoll, John Treasure), 1977 (Box 15, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-123)
  - JWT Learning Series: Management Report (Don Johnston, Ted Wilson, Alun Jones, John Treasure), 1977 (Box 15, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-124)
  - JWT Learning Series: JWT in the United States Creative Reel 1976, 1977 (Box 15, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-125)
  - JWT Managers Interviewing Techniques for Careers in Advertising, 1986 (Box 15, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-126)
  - JWT New York Talen Show Highlights, 1992 (Box 15, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-127)
  - JWT TV, Undated (Box 15, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-128)
  - Kodak spots, Undated (Box 15, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-129)
  - Layman's National Bible Committee "Excuses", 1991 (Box 15, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-130)
  - Layman's National Bible Committee "Knowledge" done by Grey Advertising, 1991 (Box 15, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-131)
  - Lincoln LS spots, Undated (Box 16, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-132)
  - Madison Ave. Satire Joe Pytka 3:30, Undated (Box 16, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-133)
  - Madison Ave. Satire Joe Pytka 3:30, Undated (Box 16, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-134)
  - Mazda Moodfilm "Japan" (JWT Frankfurt), 2000 (Box 16, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-135)
  - Mod Squad, Undated (Box 16, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-136)
  - New Business--8 Regional Spot Buyers Profiled, Undated (Box 16, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-137)
  - North American Board Meeting, 1994 (Box 16, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-138)
  - Old Commercials 1947-1982, Undated (Box 16, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-139)
    Includes: Lucky Strike, Hamm's, Falcon Convertible, Simoniz, Xerox, Commodore
  - Old JWT, Undated (Box 16, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-140)
    Includes: Lux, Kraft, Pan Am, Ken-L-Ration, Oscar Mayer, Kodak
  - Orientation Week Part II, Undated (Box 17, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-141)
  - Peggy, Carlos, Peter Kim, Mel, John, Dr. Jeckyl, Frankenstein, Undated (Box 17, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-142)
  - Peter Kim on Copy Testing, 1990 (Box 17, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-143)
  - Peter Schweitzer speech Asia Pacific, 1989 (Box 17, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-144)
  - Peter Schweitzer speech Newark FDAF, 1989 (Box 17, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-145)
  - Presentation to University of Northern Iowa Advertising and Promotion Management Class (3), Undated (Box 17, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-146)
  - Ralph Rydholm AAAA Presentation, 1985 (Box 17, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-147)
  - Recognition Award Dinner Master, 1990 (Box 17, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-148)
  - Regional Advertising Group All Staff Meeting, 1990 (Box 18, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-149)
  - Selection Reel, Undated (Box 18, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-150)
  - Smithsonian--On Advertising 60:00, Undated (Box 18, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-151)
  - Smithsonian--On Advertising 60:00, Undated (Box 18, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-152)
  - Society Bank spots, 1992 (Box 18, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-153)
  - Speedy Muffler King spots, 1990 (Box 18, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-154)
  - Talent Demo Examples, Undated (Box 18, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-155)
  - Terror in the Aisles part 1/Ford Motor Company Car Reel, 1990 (Box 18, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-156)
  - Terror in the Aisles part 2/Ford Truck vs. the Competition 42:00, 1990 (Box 18, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-157)
  - This Is J. Walter Detroit 6:00, 1988 (Box 18, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-158)
  - Tokyo Office 1985 and 1988, 1991 (Box 19, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-159)
    Includes: DeBeers, Kodak, Kellogg's, Reynolds, Suntory, Lever, Warner-Lambert, Toyo Jozo, Ford, Christian Dior, Cigna
  - Tokyo Office 1989-1991 (Box 19, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-160)
    Includes: Toyo Jozo, Esso, Unilever, American Drug, Warner-Lambert, Kellogg's, DeBeers, Suntory, Kodak
  - Tourism Spots 20:00, Undated (Box 19, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-161)
  - Turning Home Runs into Grand Slams: The Role of PR at JWT, 1993 (Box 19, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-162)
  - Toys R Us: Born to Ride, Undated (Box 19, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-163)
  - TV Advertising Seduction :30, Undated (Box 19, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-164)
  - TV Reel, Undated (Box 19, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-165)
    Includes: Ford, Bosch, Delta Dental, HAP, Pep Boys, Carhartt, Ames, Monroe
  - TV Show Compilation Reel, 1998 (Box 19, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-166)
    Includes: Bing Crosby, Louis Armstrong, Honeymooners, I Love Lucy
  - United Foundation "Crisis", 1988 (Box 19, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-167)
  - United Foundation spots, 1987 (Box 20, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-168)
  - United Way spots, 1992 (Box 20, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-169)
  - United Way spots, 1992 (Box 20, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-170)
  - University Presentation, Undated (Box 20, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-171)
    Includes: Ford, Nespray, IWS, Kraft, Nestle, Rowntree, Oxo, Persil DeBeers international commercials
  - Untouchables, Undated (Box 20, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-172)
  - Which Commercials Are Winners or Losers?, Undated (Box 20, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-173)
    Includes: Lipton, Nissan, Heinz, Plymouth, Seagrams, Kronenbourg, Carrier, Geo, Starkist, Coca-Cola
  - Video Reel of Chatham Spots, Undated (Box 20, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-174)
  - Video Tape Do Not Xray, Undated (Box 20, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-175)
  - Weekly Reel--1/13-1/27, 2003 (Box 20, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-176)
  - Version for Bank One, Undated (Box 21, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-177)
  - Weekly Reel--2/3-3/31, 2003 (Box 21, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-178)
  - Weekly Reel--4/7-5/5, 2003 (Box 21, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-179)
  - White Castle spots, 1994 (Box 21, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-180)
  - Young and Rubicam--Ford "Back to Basics", 1999 (Box 21, Video-cassette RL11360-UMATIC-181)
  - Ford Explorer "Sin Limites", Undated (Box 21, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-001)
  - TV Show Compilation Reel, 1998 (Box 21, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-002)
  - FCN England--Ford Puma, Undated (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-003)
  - FCN Germany--Ford Mondeo Launch Sardegna, 2000 (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-004)
  - Ford Explorer Master of What Isn't New :30, 2002 (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-005)
  - Ford Mustang Running Footage 9:38, Undated (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-006)
  - Ford WCF Built Ford Tough; Focus; Thunderbird; Explorer, F-Series, Undated (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-007)
  - Lincoln LS spots, 1999 (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-008)
  - Lincoln LS spot adaption, 1999 (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-009)
  - Ogilvy & Mather England--Ford of Europe TV Spots, Undated (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-010)
  - Ogilvy & Mather England--Ford Puma TV, Undated (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-011)
  - TMI Cairo (Egypt)--Ford Courier/Ford Transit TV, Undated (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-012)
  - Young and Rubicam--Lincoln Mercury, 2000 (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-013)
  - Young and Rubicam--Lincoln Mercury, 2000 (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-014)
  - Young and Rubicam--Lincoln Mercury 19 spots, 2001 (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-015)
  - Ford Explorer "Sin Limites", Undated (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-016)
  - Hawaii "What Isn't New" Graphic Elements, 2001 (Box 22, Video-cassette RL11360-BCAM-017)
  - 1987 Advertising Worldwide (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-001)
  - 1988 Advertising (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-002)
  - Ad Council: Finding Solutions 23:25, 1981 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-003)
  - Advertising Age Best TV Commercials of 1988 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-004)
  - Advertising Age Best TV Commercials of 1990 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-005)
  - AdVideo Issue 1, 1988 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-006)
  - Advideo Issue 3, 1983 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-007)
    Contents: Role of Advertising in Chrysler's Turnaround; Commercial Resource A Selection of 1983 International TV Clio Award Winners
  - Advertising Industry: The Case for Self-Regulation 24:00, 1983 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-008)
  - Adweek Best Spots, 1983 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-009)
  - Akzo Salt/Diamond Crystal "New Bag", Undated (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-010)
  - American Management Association, The Thompson Way, 1991 (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-011)
  - American Express: The Essence of the Brand 7:38, Undated (Box 23, Video-cassette RL11360-VHS-012)